{
    "1": [
        {
            "question": "What characterizes an endemic? (Chapter 1 Pg 6-7)",
            "answers": [
                "A disease that is common and persistent in populations",
                "An outbreak of a disease that affects only a small, isolated group",
                "A sudden and widespread outbreak of an infectious disease in a particular region.",
                "The global eradication of a disease"
            ],
            "correct": "A disease that is common and persistent in populations"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the disease SARS stand for? (Chapter 1 Pg 4-5)",
            "answers": [
                "Severe Allergic Reaction Syndrome",
                "Severe acute respiratory syndrome.",
                "Systemic Autoimmune Respiratory Sickness",
                "Sudden Acute Respiratory Shutdown"
            ],
            "correct": "Severe acute respiratory syndrome."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following describes Bacteria? (Chapter 1 - Pg 6-7)",
            "answers": [
                "Non-cellular particles",
                "Unicellular microorganisms",
                "Multicellular organisms",
                "Microscopic particles requiring a host cell to reproduce"
            ],
            "correct": "Unicellular microorganisms"
        },
        {
            "question": "What characterizes an epidemic? (Chapter 1 - Pg 6-7)",
            "answers": [
                "A disease that spreads slowly over several years affecting several different regions",
                "An outbreak of a disease that affects only a small, isolated group",
                "A sudden and widespread outbreak of an infectious disease in a particular region.",
                "The global eradication of a disease"
            ],
            "correct": "A sudden and widespread outbreak of an infectious disease in a particular region."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the primary goal of containment strategies in public health? (Chapter 1 pg 22-23)",
            "answers": [
                "To eliminate all infectious diseases by region",
                "To protect the global population by implementing measures to control the spread of infectious diseases",
                "To focus solely on treating individual patients",
                "To predict future outbreaks without taking any precautions"
            ],
            "correct": "To protect the global population by implementing measures to control the spread of infectious diseases"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are nucleotides primarily known for? (chapter 4 pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "Acting as enzymes in metabolic reactions",
                "Serving as the building blocks of DNA and RNA",
                "Forming the structure of cell membranes",
                "Providing energy directly to cells"
            ],
            "correct": "Serving as the building blocks of DNA and RNA"
        },
        {
            "question": "How many genes are encoded within the Ebola virus genome? (Chapter 4 - Pg 12-13)",
            "answers": [
                "Ten",
                "Eight",
                "Seven",
                "Four"
            ],
            "correct": "Seven"
        },
        {
            "question": "Approximately how many bases does the Ebola virus genome contain? (Chapter 4 - Pg 12-13)",
            "answers": [
                "7,000 bases",
                "19,000 bases",
                "12,000 bases",
                "20,000 bases"
            ],
            "correct": "19,000 bases"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is considered the most basic structural and functional unit of life? (Chapter 4 - Pg 12â€“13)",
            "answers": [
                "Cell",
                "Atom",
                "Molecule",
                "Organism"
            ],
            "correct": "Cell"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following are the four bases found in DNA? (Chapter 4 - Pg 12-13)",
            "answers": [
                "Adenine, Uracil, Guanine, Thymine",
                "Adenine, Cytosine, Guanine, Uracil",
                "Adenine, Uracil, Guanine, Ribose",
                "Adenine, Cytosine, Guanine, Thymine"
            ],
            "correct": "Adenine, Cytosine, Guanine, Thymine"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a characteristic feature of viruses? (Chapter 5 - Pg 2-3)",
            "answers": [
                "They can reproduce independently outside a host organism.",
                "They can only reproduce inside the cells of a host organism.",
                "They can reproduce in both living and non-living environments.",
                "They can grow and divide like bacteria in any environment."
            ],
            "correct": "They can only reproduce inside the cells of a host organism."
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is the correct lytic cycle order? (Chapter 5 - Pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "Attachment, replication, penetration, lysis, assembly",
                "Attachment, assembly, penetration, replication, lysis",
                "Lysis, assembly, attachment, replication, penetration",
                "Attachment, penetration, replication, assembly, lysis"
            ],
            "correct": "Attachment, penetration, replication, assembly, lysis"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the Gram stain technique reveal about bacteria? (Chapter 5 - Pg 16-17)",
            "answers": [
                "The presence of a nucleus in bacterial cells",
                "The features of a bacterial cell wall based on its ability to retain crystal violet dye.",
                "The metabolic rate of bacterial cells.",
                "The size and shape of bacterial cells under a microscope."
            ],
            "correct": "The features of a bacterial cell wall based on its ability to retain crystal violet dye."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the definition of immunity? (Chapter 6 - Pg 6-7)",
            "answers": [
                "The ability of the body to prevent pathogens from entering",
                "The ability to produce pathogens after being exposed to them.",
                "The ability to defend against a foreign pathogen after having been exposed to it.",
                "The ability to detect and neutralize only bacterial infections."
            ],
            "correct": "The ability to produce pathogens after being exposed to them."
        },
        {
            "question": "What cells are part of the innate immune system? (Chapter 6 - Pg 8-9)",
            "answers": [
                "NK-cells",
                "Macrophages",
                "B cells",
                "T cells"
            ],
            "correct": "Macrophages"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of cells cause inflammation during the immune response? (Chapter 6 - Pg 8-9)",
            "answers": [
                "Basophils and Eosinophils",
                "Neutrophils and Natural killer cells",
                "B-cells and Neutrophils",
                "Neutrophils and Macrophages"
            ],
            "correct": "Basophils and Eosinophils"
        },
        {
            "question": "What does the humoral immune response specifically involve? (Chapter 6 - Pg 18-19)",
            "answers": [
                "Destroying infected body cells",
                "Monitoring and defending the blood against pathogens.",
                "Create barriers that prevent pathogen entry.",
                "Production of antibodies by T-cells to attack pathogens."
            ],
            "correct": "Monitoring and defending the blood against pathogens."
        },
        {
            "question": "Biomarkers are measurable biological indicators that show changes in a person's health state. Which of the following types of tests are commonly used to detect biomarkers? (Chapter 7 - pg 20-21)",
            "answers": [
                "Blood pressure tests and vision tests",
                "Reflex tests and psychological evaluation",
                "Genome and antigen-based test",
                "Lung capacity tests and hearing tests"
            ],
            "correct": "Genome and antigen-based test"
        },
        {
            "question": "What type of samples are used for antigen testing? (Chapter 7 pg 22-23)",
            "answers": [
                "Urine",
                "Cerebral spinal fluid",
                "Nose swab",
                "Stool"
            ],
            "correct": "Nose swab"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the function of antifungals? (Chapter 8 pg 18-19)",
            "answers": [
                "Fight off fungal infections",
                "Fight off viral infections",
                "Fight off bacterial infections",
                "Fight off protozoa"
            ],
            "correct": "Fight off fungal infections"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is an antibiotic's mechanism of action? (Chapter 8 pg 22-23)",
            "answers": [
                "Punctures cell membrane",
                "Prevents synthesis of genetic material",
                "Prevents the release of new viral particles from host cells",
                "Inhibits RNA transcription"
            ],
            "correct": "Inhibits RNA transcription"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the last step in the drug approval process done through the FDA? (Chapter 8 pg 28-29)",
            "answers": [
                "FDA Drug Review",
                "Post-Market Clinical Research",
                "Clinical research",
                "Drug Discovery and Development"
            ],
            "correct": "Post-Market Clinical Research"
        },
		{
            "question": "What type of self-medication often comes in the form of gel or cream? (Chapter 8 pg 38-39)",
            "answers": [
                "Intranasal",
                "Topical",
                "Oral",
                "Intravenous"
            ],
            "correct": "Topical"
        },
        {
            "question": "When was the 1st hepatitis B vaccine developed? (Chapter 9 pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "1969",
                "1955",
                "1980",
                "2020"
            ],
            "correct": "1969"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which part of the vaccine stimulates the immune system but doesnâ€™t cause the disease? (Chapter 9 pg 20-21)",
            "answers": [
                "Stabilizers",
                "Preservatives",
                "Active Ingredients",
                "Trace components"
            ],
            "correct": "Active Ingredients"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following was the country that Ebola started in?",
            "answers": [
                "Nicaragua",
                "Democratic Republic of the Congo",
                "Chad",
                "Zambia"
            ],
            "correct": "Democratic Republic of the Congo"
        },
        {
            "question": "What caused the initial Ebola outbreak?",
            "answers": [
                "Bathing in unclean water",
                "Exchanging Contaminated Fluids",
                "Consuming infected meat, likely bats.",
                "Insects feeding and spreading disease."
            ],
            "correct": "Consuming infected meat, likely bats."
        },
        {
            "question": "What spreads Ebola between people?",
            "answers": [
                "Exchanging bodily fluids like blood, sweat, and tears",
                "Failing to wash hands before touching your face",
                "Touching infected surfaces",
                "Microscopic particles entering through the nose"
            ],
            "correct": "Exchanging bodily fluids like blood, sweat, and tears"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the symptoms of Ebola?",
            "answers": [
                "Severe headache, Muscle pain, Sore throat, spots of blood under your skin, Fatigue, Loss of appetite, Bloody Vomit, bloody diarrhea.",
                "Fever, Cough, Shortness of breath, Sore throat, Congestion, loss of taste or smell, Fatigue, body aches.",
                "Body chills, body aches, constant hunger, teeth rot, skin decay, bloody vomit, blindness",
                "Urination, Thirst, Weight loss, Hunger, Vision, Fatigue, Skin, Slow healing"
            ],
            "correct": "Severe headache, Muscle pain, Sore throat, spots of blood under your skin, Fatigue, Loss of appetite, Bloody Vomit, bloody diarrhea."
        },
        {
            "question": "What is a social factor that affects an individual's health (Chapter 10 pg 6-7)?",
            "answers": [
                "Genetics",
                "Immunity",
                "Stress",
                "Other health conditions"
            ],
            "correct": "Stress"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is not a chronic illness?",
            "answers": [
                "Diabetes",
                "Heart Disease",
                "Influenza",
                "Asthma"
            ],
            "correct": "Influenza"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is a common vector for transmitting diseases like malaria?",
            "answers": [
                "Ticks",
                "Flies",
                "Mosquitoes",
                "Fleas"
            ],
            "correct": "Mosquitoes"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following diseases is caused by a virus?",
            "answers": [
                "Influenza",
                "Tuberculosis",
                "Ringworm",
                "Malaria"
            ],
            "correct": "Influenza"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is the primary cause of infectious diseases?",
            "answers": [
                "Poor Nutrition",
                "Pathogens",
                "Genetic Mutations",
                "Environmental Factors"
            ],
            "correct": "Pathogens"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is responsible for copying DNA for future generations of cells? (chapter 4 pg 6-7)",
            "answers": [
                "DNA polymerase",
                "Nucleic Acid",
                "Ribonucleic acid (RNA)",
                "Transfer RNA (tRNA)"
            ],
            "correct": "DNA polymerase"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are the building blocks of DNA and RNA? (chapter 4 pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "Nucleotides",
                "Nucleic Acid",
                "Codon",
                "Amino acids"
            ],
            "correct": "Nucleotides"
        },
        {
            "question": "What phase does the duplication of genetic material occur in? (chapter 4 pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "Prophase",
                "Anaphase",
                "Transcription",
                "Translation"
            ],
            "correct": "Translation"
        },
        {
            "question": "What are nucleotides made up of? (chapter 4 pg 12-13)",
            "answers": [
                "Amino acids, lipids, carbohydrates",
                "A sugar, a phosphate group, and a nitrogenous base",
                "Proteins, enzymes, and water",
                "Fatty acids, glycerol, and cholesterol"
            ],
            "correct": "A sugar, a phosphate group, and a nitrogenous base"
        },
        {
            "question": "What makes up the backbone of DNA or RNA? (chapter 4 pg 12-13)",
            "answers": [
                "Sugar and phosphate",
                "Sugar and amino acids",
                "Amino acids and phosphate",
                "Phosphate and nucleic acid"
            ],
            "correct": "Sugar and phosphate"
        },
        {
            "question": "What is an insertion mutation? (chapter 4 pg 26-27)",
            "answers": [
                "A mutation where one or more nucleotides are removed from a gene sequence",
                "A mutation where one or more nucleotides are added to a gene sequence where they donâ€™t belong",
                "A mutation that changes one nucleotide for another in a gene sequence",
                "A mutation where a section of DNA is inverted within the gene sequence"
            ],
            "correct": "A mutation where one or more nucleotides are added to a gene sequence where they donâ€™t belong"
        },
        {
            "question": "Which of the following is true about the nucleus? (chapter 4 pg 10-11)",
            "answers": [
                "It breaks down harmful chemicals in the cell",
                "It is a membrane-bound organelle that contains tightly packed DNA",
                "It is the site of protein synthesis",
                "It is only found in prokaryotic cells"
            ],
            "correct": "It is a membrane-bound organelle that contains tightly packed DNA"
        }
    ],
	 "2": [
        { "question": "What is 10 / 2?", "answers": ["3", "5", "8", "6"], "correct": "5" },
        { "question": "Which planet is known as the Red Planet?", "answers": ["Earth", "Mars", "Jupiter", "Saturn"], "correct": "Mars" }
    ],
    "3": [
        { "question": "What is the capital of France?", "answers": ["Berlin", "London", "Paris", "Rome"], "correct": "Paris" },
        { "question": "Which element has the chemical symbol 'O'?", "answers": ["Oxygen", "Gold", "Iron", "Helium"], "correct": "Oxygen" }
    ]
}
	


    